What do rubber tyres have to do with delicious food?
橡胶轮胎与美味食物有什么关系？
The answer lies in the story of the Michelin brothers.
答案在于米其林兄弟的故事。
French inventors Edouard and Andre Michelin created the Michelin tyre company in 1889 and transformed the travel industry.
法国发明家爱德华和安德烈·米其林于1889年创立了米其林轮胎公司，并改变了旅行行业。
A few decades later, they began publishing a guide to highlight food in restaurants worth travelling for, which, of course, they'd need strong Michelin tyres to reach.
几十年后，他们开始出版一本指南，重点介绍值得前往的餐厅中的美食，而到达这些餐厅当然需要他们耐用的米其林轮胎。
Nowadays, the coveted Michelin star – an award given to only the world's finest restaurants – is one of the culinary world's highest accolades.
如今，令人向往的米其林星——一项仅授予世界上最佳餐厅的奖项——是烹饪界最高的荣誉之一。
But the rating system is somewhat shrouded in mystery.
但评级系统有些神秘。
The Michelin Guide itself says their inspectors take into account five criteria: the quality of the ingredients, the harmony of flavours, the mastery of techniques, the personality of the chef as expressed through their cuisine and consistency both across the entire menu and over time.
米其林指南表示，他们的评审员会考虑五个标准：高质量的食材、和谐调和的味道、高超的厨艺技术、厨师通过菜肴表达出的个性，以及菜单中的菜品品质是否长时间内始终如一。
But the inspectors are anonymous, and chefs are always kept in the dark about when they are going to visit.
但评审员是匿名的，厨师们永远不知道他们何时会来。"
"We're never aware of the inspectors' visit," said Julia Sedefdjian, who became France's youngest Michelin-starred chef at the age of 21.
我们从来不知道评审员的来访，"朱莉娅·塞德夫吉安说，她在21岁时成为法国最年轻的米其林星级厨师。"
"If they introduce themselves, it's only after they've eaten.
如果他们自我介绍，那也是在他们吃完之后。
And often – very often – they never introduce themselves at all."
而且绝大多数情况下——他们根本不自我介绍。"
And how much does the overall ambience of a restaurant play into the ratings?
餐厅的整体氛围对评级有多大影响？
Ideas vary.
观点各不相同。
Chef Maxime Bouttier, who has worked in Michelin-starred restaurants across France for 15 years, thinks details like white tablecloths and background piano music can help to tick boxes for inspectors.
在法国各地的米其林星级餐厅工作了15年的厨师马克西姆·布蒂埃认为，白色桌布和背景钢琴音乐等细节可以让评审员认可打分。
Despite this, Bouttier's own restaurant doesn't have tablecloths, and his clientele listen to '80s rap while dining, yet his restaurant earnt a star less than a year after opening.
尽管如此，布蒂埃自己的餐厅没有桌布，他的顾客在用餐时听80年代的说唱音乐，但他的餐厅在开业不到一年后就获得了一颗星。
The Michelin Guide says a Michelin star is awarded for the food on the plate, nothing else, and that the style and degree of formality have no bearing on the award whatsoever.
米其林指南表示，米其林星是根据盘子里的食物颁发的，仅此而已，风格和正式程度与奖项无关。
Michelin stars can make or break a chef's culinary career.
米其林星可以成就或毁掉厨师的烹饪事业。
Earning one gives a chef more recognition, more table bookings and can allow them to raise their prices.
获得一颗星能给厨师带来更多的认可、更多的订位，并且提高价格。
But there's also the risk of losing one, and with that comes a lot of pressure.
但也存在失去一颗星的风险，随之而来的是巨大的压力。